TreePeople records, 1970s-2010 LSC.2180
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Organization Files, 1970-2010 and undated
  - Water Resources Planning: A final report submitted in partial satisfaction of the requirements for the degree Doctor of Environmental Science and Engineering by John Robert Woodward, 1979 (Box 98)
  - What is TreePeople? - promotional material, undated (Box 97)
  - Wood Reuse, 1979-1980 (Box 82)
- Press Clippings, 1970-2010
  The series consists of newspaper and magazine articles about TreePeople and their activities and organizational development. The bulk of the clippings/articles are from both local and national newspapers and magazines, such as LA Daily News and Los Angeles Times. Also includes a small amount of pieces that were not clipped from their original publication. The writings represent Andy Lipkis’ founding of the organization and his role as director; the organization’s community education efforts; disaster relief work; and involvement in significant projects, such as the million tree campaign in Los Angeles prior to the 1984 Olympic Games. Additionally, there are a small number of clippings on the topic of trees as well as general environmental issues. The series is likely to include duplicative materials and there is no specific arrangement.
  - Los Angeles Times Home magazine article related to Tree People, 1983 Feb 27 (Box 99)
  - Magazine publications containing articles about TreePeople (5 folders), 1990s (Box 77)
  - Press Clippings, ca. 1970s - ca. 1990s (Box 98)
  - Press Clippings (10 folders), ca. 1970s-ca. 1990s (Box 61)
  - Press Clippings (17 folders), 1970s-1990s (Box 75)
  - Press Clippings (7 folders), 1970s-1990s (Box 76)
    May contain duplicates found elsewhere in the collection. Mixture of articles about TreePeople or general environmental issues.
  - Press Clippings (52 folders/envelopes), 1973-1974, 1980, 1983 (Box 62)
  - Press clippings related to Andy Lipkis, 1973-1979 (Box 98)
  - Press Clippings (5 folders), 1979 Aug-Apr 1980 (Box 64)
  - Press Clippings (4 folders), 1980 May-May 1981 (Box 65)
  - Press Clippings (13 folders), 1981 Jun-May 1993 (Box 66)
  - Press Clippings (75 folders/envelopes), 1983-1987 (Box 63)
  - Press Clippings (66 folders), 1988-1991 (Box 67)
  - Press Clippings (77 folders), 1991 Nov-Jan 1996 (Box 68)
  - Press Clippings, ca. 1994-2010 (Box 112)
  - Press Clippings (68 folders), 1996 (Box 69)
  - Press Clippings (75 folders), 1997 Jan-Jan 1998 (Box 70)
  - Press Clippings (87 folders), 1998 Jan-Aug 1999 (Box 71)
  - Press Clippings (68 folders), 1999 Sep-Dec 2001 (Box 72)
  - Press Clippings (7 folders), 1999-2004 (Box 73)
  - Press Clippings (6 folders), 2004-2008 (Box 74)
- Photographic Materials, 1970-2006 and undated
  The series consists of photographs, slides, negatives, and proof sheets documenting TreePeople and their activities and events. The materials represent TreePeople staff and volunteers; urban, mountain and citizen forestry work, disaster relief work, fruit tree distribution project, educational outreach and programs, such as Generation Earth, and special events, such as the Marina Freeway Run, Martin Luther King Boulevard Memorial Project, and Harvest Moon. Additionally, there are a small number of photographs/snapshots featuring Andy Lipkis and notable individuals such as Mayor Tom Bradley, Vice President Al Gore, Gregory Peck, and Betty White, among others.
  The photographs are mostly snapshots, with a small amount of professional shots. The slides are 35mm. There is no specific arrangement; however, many of the images have been grouped by like content, which is indicated by the file title or in the notes. Many of the slides are unidentified and are labeled “slide binder.” Slides have been removed from binders for preservation purposes.
  - Negatives and Proof Sheets, ca. 1977 - ca. 2003 (Box 34)
    Andy and Gregory Peck, Campo de Cahuenga, MLK Planting, Ojai Foundation, Tree Care, unidentified. With small number of slides and photographs.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 28)
  - Photographs and proof sheets, undated (Box 28)
  - Photographs, ca. 1970s - ca. 2006 (Box 32)
    30th Anniversary Gala, Campus Plantings, Million Tree Campaign (includes images of Gregory Peck and Mayor Tom Bradley), Outreach, Park Planting, Special Events and Projects, Urban Plantings, Volunteers.
  - Photographs, ca. 1930s, ca. 1980s- 2005 (Box 33)
    Andy and Kate Lipkis, Awards and Presentations, Early Coldwater Canyon Park, Education Programs, Hall House, Hilltop Deconstruction, unidentified photograph album pages (removed from album for preservation purposes), Plantings, Staff.
  - Photographs, ca. 1970s - ca. 2000s (Box 39)
    Early Mountain Days, SMM and other Mountain Plantings Later Years, Restoration.
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Proof Sheets, ca. 1970s - ca. 1980s (Box 35)
    Historic Andy, Historic TreePeople, Historic TreePeople kids.
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Proof Sheets, ca. 1970s - ca. 1980s (Box 36)
    1980 TreePeople includes images of Earth Day with Mayor Tom Bradley; 1984 Events, 1985 Events, Marina Freeway Run, Mountain Forestry, Pacific Bell Loma Alta School, Urban Forestry.
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Proof Sheets, ca. 1970s - ca. 2000s (Box 37)
    Amphitheatre Dedication, California Conservation Project, Disaster Relief, Education, Flood, Harvest Moon, Historic TreePeople, Old Coldwater Canyon Park, Plantings, Yurt Village Construction,
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Proof Sheets, ca. 1970s - ca. 2000s (Box 40)
    Africa Fruit Tree, CCP, Education Programs and Public Works, Fruit Tree Distribution.
  - Photographs, Negatives, Proof sheets, ca. 1970s - ca. 2001 (Box 41)
    Disaster Relief and TreePeople, Harvest Moon (2000-2001, includes images of Ed Begley Jr. and Betty White), unidentified negatives and proof sheets.
  - Photographs, Negatives, Proof Sheets and Slides, ca. 1970s - ca. 2000s (Box 38)
    Before and After (3.5 floppy disk and paper printouts), Harvest Moon (1987- 2002; includes images of Crosby, Stills, and Nash), Fruit Trees, unidentified slides.
  - Photographs and negatives, 1990s (Box 27)
    Appears to relate to Earth Day (1995) and Outreach Display (1992).
  - Slide binder (2 folders), undated (Box 3)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - Slide binder, 1970-1990s (Box 28)
  - Slide binder, 1976-2000 (Box 20)
  - Slide binder, 1977-1990s (Box 28)
  - Slide binder, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Slide binder, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1978-1984 (Box 2)
  - Slide binder, 1978-1980s, 1990s (Box 19)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1978-2002 (Box 18)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1979-1981 (Box 19)
  - Slides, 1980s and no date (Box 31)
    Slides in slide container boxes and envelopes. Some containers labeled with title and date.
  - Slide binder, 1980s-1990s (Box 29)
  - Slide binder, 1983 and undated (Box 18)
  - Slide binder, 1983, 1993, 1997, 2002 (Box 27)
  - Slide binder, 1984-1987 (Box 29)
  - Slide binder, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Slide binder, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Slide binder, 1986-1987, 1996 (Box 18)
    Many labeled: Africa (1987), Harvest Moon (1987), and Malibu Creek (1996). Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - Slides, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1987-1988, 1990s, 2000-2002 (Box 9)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1989-1990s (Box 5)
  - Slide binder, 1997 Jul-Dec (Box 4)
  - Slide binder, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Slide binder and audio tape, 1980s-1990s, 2001 (Box 23)
  - Slide binder and negatives (2 folders), 1990s (Box 20)
  - Slide binder with proof sheets, negatives and photographs, 1995 Jan-June (Box 6)
  - Slide binder, negatives, and photographs, 1996 (Box 23)
  - Slide binder, proof sheets and negatives, 1978, 1985, 1988, 1990s, 2001-2002 (Box 22)
  - Slide binder, proof sheets, negatives and photographs, 1996 (Box 24)
  - Slide binder, proof sheets, negatives, and photographs, 1995 (Box 7)
    With photograph of Andy Lipkis and Vice-President Al Gore, signed by Gore. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - Slide binder, proof sheets, negatives, and photographs, 1994 Feb-Nov (Box 26)
  - Slide Show slide binder, undated (Box 1)
  - Slide Show slide binder, undated (Box 2)
  - Slide Show slide binder, undated (Box 4)
  - Slides and proof sheet, 1980s-1990s (Box 28)
  - Aerial fruit trees; Culver City planting photographs, undated (Box 28)
  - Andy Lipkis with famous people, undated (Box 40)
    Ed Begley Jr., Candice Bergen, Tom Bradley, George Bush, Johnny Carson, Dalai Lama XIV, Gray Davis, Mikhail Gorbachev, Paul Hawken, Gregory Peck, Laurence J. Peter, Richard Riordan, Richard Simmons, Lily Tomlin, Antonio Villaraigosa, Zev Yaroslavsky.
  - Awards and Early Tree People slides (6 folders), 1980s (Box 11)
  - Before and After slide binder, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Bonelli Reservoir slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Broadus slide binder, 1999 Jun-July 2001, 2002 Apr (Box 15)
  - Campus Forestry-Riverside Drive Elementary photographs, proof sheet and negatives, 1996 Apr (Box 30)
  - Citizen Forestry project photographs, proof sheet and negatives, undated (Box 28)
  - Citizen Forestry-A.R. Rita Walter at CFT Planting, Virginia Street slides and proof sheet, 1996 May (Box 30)
  - Coldwater Canyon Park Earthquake Damage negatives and proof sheet, 1994 May (Box 28)
  - Coldwater Canyon Park slides, 1986, 1990 (Box 28)
  - Disaster Relief slide binder, 1978-1983 (Box 1)
  - Education slide binder, 1978-1986 (Box 11)
  - Education slide binder, 1987-1993 (Box 19)
  - Education slide binder, 1982-1987 (Box 25)
  - Environmental Education, Eco Birthday Party slides, 1996 (Box 30)
  - Fruit Tree Distributed by Vaughn Family Center slides, 1996 May (Box 30)
  - Fruit Tree Distribution slides, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Fruit Tree Program, Grove-Geosphere Project slides, 1996 May (Box 30)
  - Fruit Tree Project-Ramona Gardens slides, proof sheets and negatives, 1996 Feb 24 (Box 30)
  - Generation Earth Catalina and Generation Earth photographs, 1998 - 1999 (Box 44)
    With small number of negatives and 3.5 floppy disks.
  - Generation Earth photographs, ca. 1989 - ca. 1999 (Box 42)
    With slides and negatives.
  - Generation Earth photographs, 1999 - 2000 (Box 45)
    Generation Earth, Generation Earth - Rock the Earth. With small number of negatives.
  - Generation Earth photographs, 2000 - 2003 (Box 46)
  - Generation Earth photographs, 2003-2004 (Box 47)
    Generation Earth.
  - Generation Earth UCLA (2 folders) and Generation Earth Catalina photographs, 1998 (Box 43)
    With negatives and 3.5 floppy disks.
  - Green Series slide binder, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Harvest Moon slide binder, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Jack Alsobrooks slides, photographs and negatives, 1993 (Box 27)
  - John Earl's Springwood Slide Show slide binder, 1970s-1980s (Box 26)
  - L.A River; Adams Jr. High; Koala; Van Nuys Govt Mall slides, 1980s, 1994 (Box 27)
  - LA Arboretum slides and negatives, 1989 (Box 28)
  - Mar Vista street, Africa, and urban planting slides, 1980s (Box 28)
    With 3.5 floppy disk.
  - MLK Boulevard slides, 1990s (Box 27)
  - MLK Related photographs and negatives, 1990s (Box 30)
  - Mountain Forestry IV slide binder, 1985 Jan-Dec 1987 (Box 15)
  - Mountain Forestry photographs, 1990s (Box 28)
  - Mountain Forestry slide binder, 1976 Sep-Aug 1981 (Box 17)
  - Mountain Forestry slide binder, 1974-1976 (Box 25)
  - Mountain Forestry slide binder (in 2 folders), 1977-1984 (Box 15)
  - Mountain Forestry, Mother's Day Forest slides, 1996 May (Box 30)
  - Mountain Forestry-Big Bear negatives and proof sheets, 1996 Mar 30 (Box 30)
  - Mounted photograph of person planting a tree, ca. 1970s (Box 100)
  - Nursery slider binder, 1976-1987 (Box 16)
  - Oakwood Fruit Tree Planting slides, 1997 Mar 8 (Box 30)
  - Old Slide Shows slide binder (in 2 folders), 1980s-1990s, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Park slide binder, 1976-1978 (Box 17)
  - Park slide binder, 1980-1987 (Box 27)
  - People II slide binder, 1981 July-June 1985 (Box 9)
  - Planting of eucalyptus grove for LA Zoo's koalas in the Sepulveda Garden Center slides, 1980s (Box 27)
  - Pottings slide binder, 1975-1981 (Box 14)
  - Recycling Program slide binder (in 2 folders), 1988 Aug (Box 7)
  - Sepulveda Landfill slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Sheenway School slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Special Events slide binder, 1976-1981 (Box 17)
  - Special Events slide binder, 1982-1983 (Box 25)
  - Special Events slide binder (2 folders), 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Special Events slide binder (2 folders), 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Street Tree Replacement slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Tour of Hollenbeck slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Tree Maintenance slide binder, 1977-1982 (Box 12)
  - Tree People Staff slide binder, undated (Box 9)
  - Tree planting and children photographs and negatives, 1980s (Box 27)
  - Tree Run slide binder, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
  - Tree Types slide carousel, undated (Box 5)
    Removed from slide carousel for preservation purposes.
  - TreePeople booth at environmental convention photographs and proof sheet, undated (Box 28)
  - TreePeople photographs binder, slides and negatives, 1993 (Box 13)
  - TreePeople photographs binder, slides and negatives, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Trees Shrubs slide binder, undated (Box 13)
  - Trees slide carousel, undated (Box 20)
  - Urban Forestry selected Slides From Slide Show, undated (Box 30)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1978-1984 (Box 8)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1979-1981 (Box 10)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder, 1976-1979 (Box 24)
  - Urban Forestry slide binder (2 folders), 1985-1987 (Box 11)
  - Urban Forestry slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Urban Forestry-A/R Crossroads School slides, 1996 (Box 30)
  - Valerie Harper and TreePeople negatives and proof sheet, undated (Box 28)
  - Van Nuys slides, 1983 (Box 29)
  - We do it for LA slides, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Yurts and Moving slide binder, 2001 Jul-Jul 2002 (Box 18)
  - Yurts and Old TreePeople Officers slide binder, 2002 Apr-Dec (Box 6)
  - Slide binder, proof sheets and negatives, 1997 (Box 24)
  - Slide binder, 1998 May-Aug (Box 10)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 1998 (Box 6)
  - Slide binder, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Slide binder, 1999 Jan-May (Box 8)
  - Slide binder, 1999 May-Nov (Box 21)
  - Slide binder, 2000 Jan-Mar (Box 8)
  - Slide binder, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Slide binder, 2000 Apr-Jun (Box 22)
  - Slide binder, 2000 Apr-Jun (Box 23)
  - Slide binder, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - Slide binder, 2001 Apr-Jun (Box 10)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 2001 Jul-Feb 2002 (Box 21)
  - Slide binder (2 folders), 2001 Jan-Mar (Box 26)
  - Slide binder, 2002 Mar-June (Box 3)
  - Slide binder, 2002 Apr-May (Box 14)
  - Slide binder, 2002 June-Nov (Box 14)
  - Slide binder and proof sheets, 2002 Aug-Nov (Box 24)
- Awards, 1972-2012
  The series consists of national, state, county and city awards, honors, and commendations presented to Andy Lipkis and/or TreePeople for their continuing efforts to promote environmental awareness. Included are a mix of certificates, plaques, and three-dimensional objects. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  - Awards (plaques and three dimensional objects), 1972-2010 (Box 104)
  - Awards (plaques), 1974, 2000, 2006 (Box 103)
  - Beautiful People (The) - Honorees, 1991 (Box 109)
  - California state awards, 1990-2013 (Box 99)
  - California state awards, 1987 (Box 108)
  - City of Los Angeles Earth Day award, 1980 (Box 108)
  - Los Angeles city and county awards, 2000-2012 (Box 100)
  - Los Angeles city and county awards, 1981-1999 (Box 100)
  - Los Angeles City Department of Recreation and Parks award, 1997 (Box 100)
  - National awards, 1972-2013 (Box 99)
  - Van Nuys Sherman Oaks Ecology Council award, 1980 (Box 99)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1970-2003 and undated
  The series consists of audio cassettes, DVDs, and assorted video formats. The materials document television interviews and news coverage of TreePeople’s environmental efforts, as well as local, national, and international community activities and events, such as the King Boulevard Memorial Project, Million Tree Campaign, Harvest Moon fundraising events, and other outreach programs. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  - Audio and digital video cassette tapes, ca. 1970s - ca. 2000s (Box 48)
    Some cassettes may contain labels related to subject matter of recording.
  - Audio and video cassette tapes (22 items), ca. 1980s - ca. 2000s (Box 59)
    Some tapes may contain labels related to subject matter of recording
  - BetaCam SP tapes and BetaCam tapes containing media clips (28 items), 1991-1997 (Box 56)
    Tapes numbered 24-37. A list of tapes is included in the box. Each tape case contains listing of clip contents.
  - BetaCam SP tapes containing media clips (11 items), 1991-1994 (Box 55)
    Tapes numbered 21-23. A list of tapes is included in the box. Each tape case contains listing of clip contents.
  - BetaCam SP tapes containing media clips (14 items), 1984-2003 (Box 54)
    Tapes numbered 2-20 and 38-41. A list of tapes is included in the box. Each tape case contains listing of clip contents.
  - DVDs (49 items), 1984-2003 (Box 51)
    DVDs numbered 2-221. List of DVDs included in box. Each DVD case contains listing of clip contents.
  - VHS Tapes containing media clips (23 items), 1983-2003 (Box 53)
    Tapes numbered 42-221. A list of tapes is included in the box. Each tape case contains listing of clip contents.
  - VHS Tapes containing media clips (24 items), 1984-2003 (Box 52)
    Tapes numbered 2-41. A list of tapes is included in the box. Each tape case contains listing of clip contents.
  - VHS tapes (29 items), ca. 1980s - ca. 2000s (Box 50)
    Some tapes may contain labels related to subject matter of recording.
  - VHS tapes (31 items), undated (Box 58)
    Some videos may contain labels related to subject matter of recording.
  - VHS tapes (37 items), ca. 1980s - ca. 2000s (Box 49)
  - VHS tapes (6 items), undated (Box 57)
  - Video cassette tapes and DVDs (38 items), ca. 1990s - ca. 2000s (Box 60)
    Some items may contain labels related to subject matter of recording. A portion of the tapes are numbered and a coincide to a list of recordings included in the box. (The list does not include every tape in the box.)